<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>AlphaBack - Get Paid to Look at NFTs</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Get Paid to Look at NFTs</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 20:49:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>AlphaBack - Get Paid to Look at NFTs</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Content Performance &#038; Company Ops</title>
		<link>./../../../content-performance-review-company-ops/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rod Fuentes]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 19:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Retro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=240</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>GM frens, our stakeholder list is growing and Gmail is starting to complain about sender volume. As a result, future updates will be posted on our blog and sent out via a newsletter service (Mailchimp) rather than individual emails. So if you&#8217;ve been hesitantly opening my updates, here&#8217;s your chance to let them fade into [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../content-performance-review-company-ops/index.html">Content Performance &#038; Company Ops</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">AlphaBack</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>GM frens, our stakeholder list is growing and Gmail is starting to complain about sender volume. As a result, future updates will be posted on <a href="./../../../category/retro/index.html">our blog</a> and sent out via a newsletter service (Mailchimp) rather than individual emails. So if you&#8217;ve been hesitantly opening my updates, here&#8217;s your chance to let them fade into the background <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f605.png" alt="😅" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> But if you love hearing from us, then make sure you <a href="http://eepurl.com/h4pPkz">opt-in to our email list here</a>!</p>



<h3>Highlights</h3>



<ul><li><strong>Fundraising</strong>. We received two more introductions to follower-funds and one more written commitment. All told, the end is near and we&#8217;re excited to conclude our fundraising.</li><li><strong>Exploring SSP Shortcut</strong>. We explored fulfilling ad inventory immediately by using supply side platforms (SSP). We successfully opened accounts with two SSPs – no small feat as we must meet their stringent publisher requirements.</li><li><strong>Monitoring Content Series</strong>. As you know, we published a content marketing experiment where we <a href="./../../../category/twitter-spaces-summaries/index.html">summarize popular Twitter Spaces</a>. The blog is now 37% of page views (&#8220;PV&#8221;) in the last 14 days, up 110% from the prior 14 day period. Overall traffic is up 93% in the same time period, from 188 PV to 364 PV. Our goal is to generate ~600 PV per Summary over a 12 week period to consider that experiment a scalable success.</li></ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img width="1024" height="616" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-10-1024x616.png" alt="" class="wp-image-256" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-10-1024x616.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-10-300x181.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-10-768x462.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-10-1536x925.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-10-1200x722.png 1200w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-10.png 1766w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>Google Analytics showing performance of the blog posts relative to overall site traffic.</figcaption></figure>



<ul><li><strong>Company Ops</strong>. We spent a few cycles polishing our surface areas, such as managing our signed agreements, setting up Carta for cap table management, and obtaining company insurance.</li></ul>



<h3>Challenges</h3>



<ul><li><strong>SSP Limitations</strong>. Despite opening accounts, various SSP limitations hinder our ability to take this shortcut. Instead, we&#8217;ll redouble efforts on the product leaderboard feature.</li></ul>



<h3>Asks</h3>



<ul><li>Do you know an NFT or Crypto project that&#8217;s interested in getting free exposure? Send me a note so we can collaborate with them.</li></ul>



<p>As usual, we&#8217;re grateful for your ongoing support <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f64f.png" alt="🙏" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/alpha-back/oecacmanfecanoehhmhmjmpdlhffiihe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Install the free AlphaBack Browser Extension</a>&nbsp;today!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../content-performance-review-company-ops/index.html">Content Performance &#038; Company Ops</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">AlphaBack</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NFT Marketing: Brands, Platforms, and MLM</title>
		<link>./../../../nft-marketing-brands-platforms-and-mlm/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rod Fuentes]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 20:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Twitter Spaces Summaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter Spaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=271</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In this Twitter Spaces, Evil Plan Inc. and friends discuss NFT marketing tactics across brands, drawing comparisons to MLM schemes.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../nft-marketing-brands-platforms-and-mlm/index.html">NFT Marketing: Brands, Platforms, and MLM</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">AlphaBack</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In this <em>Twitter Spaces Summary</em> (#TSS) of <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Totally Uninformed Opinions on NFTs, Web3, Gaming, Tech, Startups &amp; VC</span>, hosts @EvilPlanInc, @SaylessLarry, and @jservesworld discuss NFT marketing tactics across brands, drawing comparisons to multi-level marketing (MLM) schemes.</p>



<p><em>n.b. Summaries are edited for brevity and inconsistencies may occur due to crosstalk or audio quality. The content presented is not financial advice. Do your own research and review <a href="#disclaimerandrisks">the disclaimer below</a>.</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h2>Totally Uninformed Opinions on NFT Marketing, Web3, and VC</h2>



<p><a href="https://twitter.com/@EvilPlanIncCo">Evil Plan Inc.</a> hosted the daily show, Totally Uninformed Opinions on NFTs, Web3, Gaming, Tech, Startups &amp; VC on Aug. 17, 2022, with a runtime of <strong>41 hours</strong> and 6.3K people tuning in. </p>



<p>Note, the show was so long and covered various topics unrelated to NFTs. Here is a summary of that Twitter Spaces with respect to NFT and crypto.</p>



<h2>NFT Marketing is like MLM Schemes</h2>



<ul type="rich"><li><strong>Bombay</strong> highlights how he used NFT communities to build his network. Now he can help projects with NFT marketing.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Noah Patterson</strong> mentions that Azuki spent $400,000 to build and market its NFT project. The key to successful NFT marketing is getting people to buy your project via psychology.</li><li><strong>SoldierSilent</strong> says that MLM schemes have seven principles of influence. The important element is that one person influences another. It&#8217;s all about social proof where people are selling Tupperware from house to house. <strong>SoldierSilent</strong> says he would pitch to a person, and then use that person to get introductions to the rest of their network<strong>. </strong>Using MLM strategy is all about creating an obligation to buy from a person you know. </li><li><strong>Noah Patterson</strong> compares MLMs to crypto: if you buy-in at the top (e.g., first), then you can sell to the rest and capture the most value. Most projects are cookie cutter, and it all comes down to the NFT marketing. Like MLM, crypto is all about having getting your friends to see the project.</li><li><strong>CryptoBella</strong> says she watched friends spin up NFT marketing companies in the last year. <strong>Noah Patterson</strong> chides that anyone who&#8217;s been in the NFT space for more than six months is a guru NFT marketer <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f602.png" alt="😂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></li></ul>



<h2>Blockbuster Making Moves into NFTs</h2>



<ul><li><strong>Noah Patterson</strong> mentions that web3 is a new space that people want to become relevant in. In fact, <a href="https://retailtechinnovationhub.com/home/2022/7/25/blockbuster-back-from-the-grave-linked-with-nfts-move">there&#8217;s rumors that Blockbuster</a> is getting into the NFT space. Their advantage: people will trust the Blockbuster brand regardless of what they release.</li><li><strong>Jak</strong> believes Blockbuster will have an unlimited budget, and as a web3 project, they&#8217;ll be seeking an NFT influencer. <strong>Noah Patterson</strong> says he&#8217;d recommend someone from the gaming community (esp. fighting games) because of how many followers they have. Again, it&#8217;s all about NFT marketing.</li></ul>



<h2>PlayNFT Launches NFT Marketplace For Twitch &amp; YouTube Streamers</h2>



<ul><li><strong>CryptoBella</strong> talks about a new NFT utility platform called <a href="https://egamers.io/playnft-launches-nft-marketplace-for-twitch-youtube-streamers-worldwide/">PlayNFT</a>. It&#8217;s like Twitch or YouTube but gamers can have an NFT attached to their account so that they can sell and market their NFTs.<strong> </strong>Some 260 streamers signed up already. Users also get their own storefront for NFT marketing purposes, allowing them to offer their own branded tokens.</li></ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="576" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-11-1024x576.png" alt="PlayNFT offers strong NFT marketing opportunities by enabling users to offer their own tokens in a storefront." class="wp-image-324" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-11-1024x576.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-11-300x169.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-11-768x432.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-11.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<ul><li>Speaking about video streamers, <strong>Noah Patterson</strong> mentions that OnlyFans couldn&#8217;t get VC backing because the content was too explicit. This is an opportunity for crypto. In fact, there&#8217;s one company that offers <a href="https://www.livecoinwatch.com/price/Porn-PORN">Porn Coin</a> that compensates sex workers via an OnlyFans like clone site.</li><li><strong>CryptoBella</strong> likes the notion of a streaming platform that allows creators to control what NFTs they hold and offer.</li><li><strong>Jak</strong> mentions that OpenSea would be better off without NSFW content. At least it&#8217;s not on OpenSea&#8217;s servers because the content is technically hosted on-chain. </li><li>Speaking of NFSW, <strong>MetaRuth_Eth</strong> says she&#8217;s excited for the evolution of technology and its safety features for OnlyFans&#8217; creators. Crypto is building a safer bridge from web2 to web2.5 and eventually to web3 for women. Similarly, new platforms can track how many people come into a metaverse space for sex workers, how long patrons stood in an area, and sell the virtual space as an NFT. <strong>MetaRuth_Eth</strong> says that she sits on the Immersive Emerging Technologies committee for the Indian Women&#8217;s Chamber of Commerce, and she has been showing that organization these features, leading to new perspectives.</li></ul>



<h2>Post-Merge Consequences: Higher APR Yields and Multi-Generation NFTs</h2>



<ul><li><strong>SoldierSilent</strong> says they sat in a presentation from a Coinbase product manager on staking. Prediction: APR yields will increase 50% post merge. As a result, the industry might go from 3% &#8211; 4% APR right now to 4% &#8211; 5% after the merge.</li><li><strong>SoldierSilent</strong> talks about how the difference between POW and POS is that the staking period is undetermined. He&#8217;s getting more ETH for staking compared to now, because POW is limited by capital.</li><li><strong>Dr. Nope</strong> says the ecosystem is where it is, and at the end of the day, the Merge is going to happen. <strong>Noah Patterson</strong> asks if NFTs should take on generation-1 and generation-2 designation for NFT marketing purposes. <strong>Dr. Nope</strong> says that&#8217;s a community choice. <strong>Noah Patterson</strong> talks about how it&#8217;s like when a country reissues currency, and it&#8217;s not recognized. It&#8217;s disruptive to the market.</li><li><strong>Dr. Nope</strong> the Merge will be a slow process. It&#8217;s a mission critical item for the Ethereum Foundation, and they’re running parallel chains to check errors, among other things. The switchover will be much more anti-climatic than people seem to believe.</li><li><strong>Dr. Nope</strong> believes this is an opportunity to in on the ground floor –&nbsp;again. He predicts Ethereum will reach $4k USD per ETH. But if people want it to be a common medium of exchange, crypto needs to achieve price stability. </li></ul>



<h2>More People into Crypto Requires Stability and Lower Risk Perception</h2>



<ul><li><strong>Dr. Nope</strong> says that most people’s risk tolerance is not high, so high risk assets are not attractive. Crypto has to smooth out the volatility to get pension funds involved.</li><li><strong>SoldierSilent</strong> notes that they have been trying to bring some of their friends into NFTs. The challenge is changing the public perception of crypto; until then it&#8217;ll be a high risk asset. The industry needs to self-police and work on its public image in order to bring mass adoption. Positive, non-spammy NFT marketing plays an important role in that capacity.</li><li><strong>Noah Patterson</strong> says people are content to put money in the bank with 1% &#8211; 2% percent returns. If projects can show 5% returns reliably, that&#8217;s going to be huge. But <strong>Dr. Nope</strong> emphasizes slow, sustained growth with minimal price action is the ideal path. Separately, retailers don&#8217;t accept crypto because they’re dealing with vendors who want fiat. It&#8217;s not feasible or realistic to force high risk tolerance down the supply chain.</li></ul>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Liked this summary? You may also <a href="./../../../category/twitter-spaces-summaries/index.html">enjoy these</a>:</p>



<div class="wp-container-2 wp-block-query"><ul class="wp-container-1 wp-block-post-template"><li class="wp-block-post post-271 post type-post status-publish format-standard has-post-thumbnail hentry category-twitter-spaces-summaries tag-crypto tag-nfts tag-twitter-spaces tag-web3">
<h5 class="has-text-align-center wp-block-post-title"><a href="./../../../nft-marketing-brands-platforms-and-mlm/index.html" target="_self" rel="">NFT Marketing: Brands, Platforms, and MLM</a></h5>

<figure class="alignwide wp-block-post-featured-image"><a href="./../../../nft-marketing-brands-platforms-and-mlm/index.html"><img width="1174" height="919" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/totally-uninformed.png" class="attachment-post-thumbnail size-post-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="NFT Marketing: Brands, Platforms, and MLM" loading="lazy" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/totally-uninformed.png 1174w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/totally-uninformed-300x235.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/totally-uninformed-1024x802.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/totally-uninformed-768x601.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1174px) 100vw, 1174px" /></a></figure>

<div class="wp-block-post-excerpt"><p class="wp-block-post-excerpt__excerpt">In this Twitter Spaces, Evil Plan Inc. and friends discuss NFT marketing tactics across brands, drawing comparisons to MLM schemes.</p><p class="wp-block-post-excerpt__more-text"><a class="wp-block-post-excerpt__more-link" href="./../../../nft-marketing-brands-platforms-and-mlm/index.html">Read More</a></p></div>
</li><li class="wp-block-post post-195 post type-post status-publish format-standard has-post-thumbnail hentry category-nfts category-twitter-spaces-summaries tag-8aliens tag-nfts tag-non-fungible-tokens tag-twitter-spaces">
<h5 class="has-text-align-center wp-block-post-title"><a href="./../../../8aliens-nft-market-trends/index.html" target="_self" rel="">8Aliens &#038; NFT Market Trends</a></h5>

<figure class="alignwide wp-block-post-featured-image"><a href="./../../../8aliens-nft-market-trends/index.html"><img width="1200" height="720" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-8-1200x720.png" class="attachment-post-thumbnail size-post-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="8Aliens &#038; NFT Market Trends" loading="lazy" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-8-1200x720.png 1200w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-8-300x180.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-8-1024x614.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-8-768x461.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-8-1536x922.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-8-2048x1229.png 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-8-1980x1188.png 1980w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></a></figure>

<div class="wp-block-post-excerpt"><p class="wp-block-post-excerpt__excerpt">In this Twitter Spaces Summary (#TSS) of the NFT Morning Show, Pio.eth and friends review the latest NFT market trends and discuss 8Aliens.</p><p class="wp-block-post-excerpt__more-text"><a class="wp-block-post-excerpt__more-link" href="./../../../8aliens-nft-market-trends/index.html">Read More</a></p></div>
</li></ul></div>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p id="disclaimerandrisks"><em>Disclaimer &amp; Risks: This summary is for informational and entertainment purposes only and should not be relied upon as a basis for investment decisions. The host and guest may hold NFTs mentioned on the show, but that is not an endorsement or recommendation to buy any tokens or NFTs mentioned. Please do not follow any opinion as a specific strategy. Using crypto applications, wallets, protocols, and tools may expose users to risks including, but not limited to, smart contract bugs, systemic risk, flashloan attacks, economic incentive failures, liquidity crises, admin key exploits, governance exploits, and pegged assets such as stablecoins or tokenized BTC de-pegging.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../nft-marketing-brands-platforms-and-mlm/index.html">NFT Marketing: Brands, Platforms, and MLM</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">AlphaBack</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Growth Marketing &#038; Fundraising Milestone</title>
		<link>./../../../growth-marketing-fundraising-milestone/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rod Fuentes]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 01:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Retro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growth marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[non-fungible tokens]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=162</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We're excited to lay the foundation of our growth marketing engine, and Commonwealth Asset Management (CWAM) is leading our fundraising 🎉</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../growth-marketing-fundraising-milestone/index.html">Growth Marketing &#038; Fundraising Milestone</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">AlphaBack</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>GM, GA, and GN! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f44b.png" alt="👋" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> We&#8217;re pleased to announce that Commonwealth Asset Management (CWAM) joined our cap table <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f389.png" alt="🎉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Further, we laid the foundation of our growth marketing engine this week. More on that in the Highlights section, so keep reading!</p>



<h3>Highlights</h3>



<ul><li><strong>Fundraising</strong>. CWAM, a Los Angeles based asset management platform with $1.7B in assets and 27 team members, joined our cap table. We&#8217;re excited to partner with their crypto-focused team, bringing us just past $1.6M in written commitments. We&#8217;ll allocate the remaining $385,000 in the next few weeks, and soon we&#8217;ll wrap up fundraising to focus 100% on product and growth marketing <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f4aa.png" alt="💪" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></li><li><strong>Won Pitch Competition</strong>. We competed in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cy7z7LekQgg&amp;t=1690s">Blockrocket&#8217;s monthly startup pitch competition</a> and won 1st Place!  </li><li><strong>Launched Blog</strong>. We migrated from Medium to our own blog, hosted in our domain&#8217;s subdirectory for maximum SEO and to generate inbound traffic. You&#8217;ll see <a href="./../../../koala-bot-club-talks-game-automation/index.html">more posts there</a>, as we turn on our growth marketing engine.</li><li><strong>Product Led Growth</strong>. We discussed and mocked a leaderboard feature so we can request a stronger call-to-action from NFT collections – pushing their communities to install our browser extension so that their members can upvote their NFTs. </li></ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="640" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-3-1024x640.png" alt="This Figma mockup shows a leaderboard feature that may power our growth marketing." class="wp-image-163" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-3-1024x640.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-3-300x188.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-3-768x480.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-3-1536x960.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-3-2048x1280.png 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-3-1200x750.png 1200w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/08/image-3-1980x1238.png 1980w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>We&#8217;re focusing on user growth marketing because we&#8217;re facing a classic chicken-and-egg challenge. We believe the solution is to attract a large user base in order to attract our first advertisers. Once advertisers initiate payments, we&#8217;ll pay users, which will attract more users – and thus, more advertisers.</p>



<h3>Challenges</h3>



<ul><li>None <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f440.png" alt="👀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></li></ul>



<h3>Asks</h3>



<ul><li>Do you know anyone who is or was at <a href="https://www.rakuten.com/sem2/button.htm">Rakuten</a> or <a href="https://honey.is/">Honey</a>? We&#8217;d love to get their insights on growth marketing and partnership strategy. </li></ul>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/alpha-back/oecacmanfecanoehhmhmjmpdlhffiihe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Install the free AlphaBack Browser Extension</a> today!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../growth-marketing-fundraising-milestone/index.html">Growth Marketing &#038; Fundraising Milestone</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">AlphaBack</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Institutional Capital for NFT Promotions &#038; Progress Upgradeable Contracts</title>
		<link>./../../../institutional-capital-upgradeable-contracts/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rod Fuentes]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 19:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Retro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[non-fungible tokens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This week was delightful! We released upgradeable contracts and analytics in staging, and we welcomed an institutional investor on our cap table. We&#8217;re making good progress toward onboarding our first 10,000 NFT-friendly users. Highlights Fundraising. We’re excited to welcome Hashkey Capital in our round, an institutional fund with over 200 portfolio companies that has been [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../institutional-capital-upgradeable-contracts/index.html">Institutional Capital for NFT Promotions &#038; Progress Upgradeable Contracts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">AlphaBack</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This week was delightful! We released upgradeable contracts and analytics in staging, and we welcomed an institutional investor on our cap table. We&#8217;re making good progress toward onboarding our first 10,000 NFT-friendly users.</p>



<h3>Highlights</h3>



<ul><li><strong>Fundraising</strong>. We’re excited to welcome <strong>Hashkey Capital</strong> in our round, an institutional fund with over 200 portfolio companies that has been investing exclusively in blockchain technology since 2015.</li><li><strong>Upgradeable contracts</strong>. As <a href="./../../../upgradeable-contracts-more-fundraising/index.html">mentioned last week</a>, we&#8217;ve been working on upgradeable smart contracts. This week, we released that code in our staging environment. Next, we’ll conduct QA and aim for a production release in the next sprint.</li><li><strong>Analytics</strong>. We can now track connected wallets, enabling us to identify users who should receive payments for viewing NFTs <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f911.png" alt="🤑" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></li></ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*MmBV0wmhmicchNsavaJ4yQ.png" alt="Analytics show a user's wallet ID connected to AlphaBack, an extension that pays users to look at NFTs"/></figure>



<h3>Challenges</h3>



<ul><li><strong>Deployments</strong>. A new code package introduced conflicting dependencies. We lost two days of dev time diagnosing and fixing that issue in our staging environment. Production systems were not affected.</li></ul>



<h3>Asks</h3>



<ul><li>We’re working on user research and mockups of our next NFT discovery user experience. Signup for a <a href="https://calendly.com/rodfuentes/office-hours" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">short user interview here</a>.</li><li>Do you know any NFT collections who would be interested in a simple win-win collaboration? We’ll promote them on AlphaBack, and they encourage their community to install our extension. Here are a few that we’re approaching:</li></ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*jp0I-lq13J5ZJvPRVIYv-A.png" alt=""/></figure>



<h3>Food for&nbsp;Thought</h3>



<p>We’ve been thinking about traditional advertising models and how we can leverage them to provide users with more yield in the future.</p>



<p>For instance, we can empower users to <em>control</em> their advertising experience, allowing them to offer more data to advertisers in exchange for greater payments. In one scenario, users may get a multiplier on rewards if they connect more wallets. Or perhaps users opt-in to share browser activity and history, leading to another multiplier. We believe these will be rich data sources in the future (post-cookie) advertising world — and users should benefit directly from offering their data.</p>



<p>Additionally, we could reward users based on the number of ad views they generate in their typical browsing experience. Cost-per-click campaigns are also possible in the future, where users earn a percentage of each paid click. Similarly, we could introduce cost-per-action campaigns that are uniquely tied to wallet addresses, encouraging higher rewards for users and conversions for advertisers.</p>



<p>That said, we leave those ideas for future implementation because they require careful product development to prevent abuse. Any model where the user benefits from doing more of the paid activity presents a moral hazard. For example, did the user click on the ad to earn money, or were they genuinely interested in the advertised product or NFT? Fortunately, advertising fraud is an old problem with well-established methods for detecting such activity.</p>



<p>But, first things first, <em>we must grow our user base</em> to make all of this possible. So I want to thank you for your support as we climb to 1M users.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/alpha-back/oecacmanfecanoehhmhmjmpdlhffiihe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Install the AlphaBack Browser Extension</a> today!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../institutional-capital-upgradeable-contracts/index.html">Institutional Capital for NFT Promotions &#038; Progress Upgradeable Contracts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">AlphaBack</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Debuted AlphaBack at Tachyon’s Demo Day</title>
		<link>./../../../debuted-alphaback-at-tachyons-demo-day/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rod Fuentes]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Retro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accelerator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DAO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[demoday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[non-fungible tokens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[startups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=98</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We concluded our 12-week accelerator program with a bang. On June 30, 2022, we debuted AlphaBack.xyz at Tachyon’s Demo Day using the Stonks platform. What is AlphaBack? With AlphaBack, users see a promoted NFT — instead of a search bar — when they open a new browser tab. Advertisers pay to promote there because users open ~50 tabs per [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../debuted-alphaback-at-tachyons-demo-day/index.html">Debuted AlphaBack at Tachyon’s Demo Day</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">AlphaBack</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We concluded our 12-week accelerator program with a bang. On June 30, 2022, we debuted<a href="https://alphaback.xyz/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"> AlphaBack.xyz</a> at Tachyon’s Demo Day using the Stonks platform.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*rI2q6Sg6eEYdAYdF0f3dUg.png" alt="A screenshot of what viewers saw during Tachyon's Demo Day on June 30th."/></figure>



<h3>What is AlphaBack?</h3>



<p>With AlphaBack, users see a promoted NFT — instead of a search bar — when they open a new browser tab. Advertisers pay to promote there because users open ~50 tabs per day, averaging 3+ min. of engagement. Via smart contracts, 70% of that money goes to users and 30% goes to our DAO. In time,</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>our DAO will be the biggest web3 ad / data network that’s owned by the community, for the community.</p></blockquote>



<p>The most exciting part of AlphaBack is that we have a <strong>huge opportunity to shape the future of advertising in a post-cookie, web3 world</strong>. Let’s unpack that a bit.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*Hn0MTJjPU0H-dLmt_6WJYQ.jpeg" alt=""/><figcaption>AlphaBack converts your “new browser tab” into an NFT-viewing experience – plus you get paid USDC if that NFT was a paid promotion.</figcaption></figure>



<p>In the last ad:tech bull run, companies like BlueKai and LiveRamp built huge businesses leveraging cookies to create data targeting segments. Advertisers paid an average of $3 per 1,000 impressions (CPM) to enable targeting based on those segments, such as job titles, affinities, and more. That’s <em>on top</em> of the average $2.80 CPM for the ad placement — showing that the targeting data is just as valuable (if not more so) than the ad inventory itself. But the last five years weakened the foundations of cookie-based targeting thanks to GDPR, CCPA, and Apple’s privacy-enhancing moves. And yet advertisers will continue to crave targeting data for their ad campaigns.</p>



<h3>The Future of Ad Targeting</h3>



<p>Web3 presents an opportunity to provide appropriate targeting and privacy protections. Imagine a world where millions of AlphaBack users have connected their wallet and consented to be part of our community-owned ad network. With that, we could <strong>create a Device-ID-to-Wallet-Address graph, mapping users’ wallet activity to advertise-able devices</strong>. Unlike cookies, user wallet activity is already public on chain, and thus there should be fewer privacy concerns. Armed with such a device-to-wallet graph would enable us to <strong>sell and activate targeting data on <em>any ad network</em></strong> (such as Google, Facebook, Twitter, etc.), in addition to our ad units on new browser tabs. That is a huge opportunity.</p>



<p>We believe that <strong>user wallet activity is the next frontier of ad targeting</strong>, which will be vastly more powerful than cookie segments inferred by user form submissions and page visits. For example, want to target DeFi users that have swapped ETH to USDC in the past 3 months? Easy. Or perhaps you want to target all users who purchased a Bored Ape Yacht Club NFT for more than 50 ETH? Done. Creating <strong>targetable user personas based on <em>actual</em> wallet activity is a boon to advertisers</strong> that want to go beyond inferred age, sex, location, and income brackets. In the future, advertisers should be able to target wallet addresses that have spent 5 ETH in the last 90 days or Whales who have more than 100 ETH. That <em>certainty</em> about the targeting data is unheard of today and will unleash increased ad spend because suddenly it becomes justifiable to spend more to target higher value personas.</p>



<h3>Balancing User Privacy and Advertiser Targeting</h3>



<p>But the vision above will require the right balance between protecting privacy and leveraging user data for targeting. Enter the DAO-owned ad network — a product that’s for the community, by the community.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>We believe that a community-owned and operated ad network will be best positioned to strike the necessary balance between users and advertisers because the user’s voice will be a part of the process.</p></blockquote>



<p>Users (and their data) will be more than just monetizable eyeballs; they will get to decide how much of their privacy they want to monetize — and then benefit directly from that monetization. We believe this puts the incentives in the right place, yielding a productive negotiation between Users and Advertisers.</p>



<p>We hope you are as excited as we are to create a better advertising future that’s built on mutual respect and blockchain-enabled trust.</p>



<h3>What about NFT Deals after Demo Day?</h3>



<p>NFTDeals.xyz is a front-end to an NFT auction protocol that we built. In the coming months, we’ll allow the community to determine its future direction. <a href="https://discord.gg/uKQgkteu72" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Join our Discord server</a> if you’re interested in participating in that discussion.</p>



<p>As founders, however, we will dedicate our energy to <a href="https://alphaback.xyz/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">AlphaBack</a> because we believe that is the growth opportunity in this market. This means that we will not be hosting auctions ourselves in the near term. But that’s the beauty of a permissionless protocol: <em>you</em> can host an auction whenever you want without having to partner with us directly. Simply interact with the published smart contracts in our backend portal or via EtherScan!</p>



<h3>Highlights</h3>



<ul><li><strong>Fundraising.</strong> On June 30, 2022, we debuted our product at Tachyon’s Demo Day using <a href="https://stonks.com/deal/alphaback" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">the Stonks platform</a>. It was an incredible event, with over 350 viewers watching the livestream. We received 23 introduction requests from investors, totaling $2M worth of interest.</li><li><strong>The Pivot, Redux</strong>. Last week we <a href="https://medium.com/nftdeals/nft-deals-week-12-retro-9d1b6c8ced8e" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">began exploring a soft pivot</a> where we would sell the NFT Deals’ backend tooling to major brands. But several customer interviews and investor discussions later, we learned that was not going to be the best opportunity for us in the current market. Simply stated, brands have 12- to 18-month long sales cycles that, combined with the bear market, will result in <em>limited opportunities to validate product market fit</em>. While we considered pursuing that option — akin to pushing a boulder uphill — we realized that AlphaBack’s users were growing at 155% compounded daily — like a snowball rolling downhill. Not bad given that we haven’t been actively marketing AlphaBack, besides telling people about it at NFT NYC.</li></ul>



<h3>Obstacles</h3>



<ul><li><strong>Minimizing Gas Fees.</strong> The first MVP is almost complete, with gas fee minimization for multi-call USDC payments as the final step. We don’t want to over-engineer the process, so this version will support up to 100K users. But current estimates show that it will cost approximately $172 in gas fees on Polygon to send USDC to that many users. Not ideal to say the least. We are exploring other options so that users earn as much as possible from advertisers.</li></ul>



<h3>How You Can&nbsp;Help</h3>



<ul><li>Our demo day showed us that there is <a href="./../../../institutional-capital-upgradeable-contracts/index.html">strong investor interest</a>, so we’re putting together a pre-seed round. Reply if you have intros to investors who are interested in (1) a veteran team of 10Xers who’ve been working together for ten years, (2) community ownership trends, or (3) ad targeting in a web3, post-cookie world.</li></ul>



<p>Thanks again for your ongoing support <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f64f.png" alt="🙏" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../debuted-alphaback-at-tachyons-demo-day/index.html">Debuted AlphaBack at Tachyon’s Demo Day</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">AlphaBack</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
